<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>guides on Nathan Catania</title>
    <link>https://nathancatania.com/tags/guides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in guides on Nathan Catania</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nathancatania.com/tags/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Netskope Cloud Exchange</title>
      <link>https://nathancatania.com/posts/deploy-netskope-cloud-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nathancatania.com/posts/deploy-netskope-cloud-exchange/</guid>
      <description>The thoughts, and opinions in this post are my own and do not reflect those of Netskope. All content in this post is my own and is not endorsed by Netskope. Please follow this guide at your own risk.&#xA;Changelog:&#xA;1st Mar, 2022: Initial post 7th Dec, 2022: Updated guide for Cloud Exchange 4.0. What is Cloud Exchange? Cloud Exchange (CE) is a platform (free for all Netskope customers) that facilitates the exchange of information between your various security and operations platforms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Set up Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) for free</title>
      <link>https://nathancatania.com/posts/set-up-azure-active-directory-for-your-homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nathancatania.com/posts/set-up-azure-active-directory-for-your-homelab/</guid>
      <description>Get an Azure Free Account Before you start, you will need to sign up for a free Azure account: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-au/free/&#xA;This gives you some Azure services, like Windows &amp;amp; Linux VMs, free for 12 months, while other Azure services (like Azure Active Directory) are free permanently up to certain usage limits.&#xA;With Azure AD free, you can freely create users and groups, but groups cannot be assigned and synchronized to enterprise applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Windows Server with an Azure Free Account</title>
      <link>https://nathancatania.com/posts/deploying-windows-server-2019-with-an-azure-free-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nathancatania.com/posts/deploying-windows-server-2019-with-an-azure-free-account/</guid>
      <description>Get an Azure Free Account Before you start, you will need to sign up for a free Azure account: https://azure.microsoft.com/en-au/free/&#xA;This gives you some Azure services, like Windows &amp;amp; Linux VMs, free for 12 months, while other Azure services (like Azure Active Directory) are free permanently up to certain usage limits.&#xA;To see everything included in the free account, click here.&#xA;Note: Don&amp;rsquo;t expect the server deployed under the free tier to be fast - we are limited to 1GB RAM and 1 vCPU with the B1s instance size.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[How to] Upgrade your PS4 to an SSD</title>
      <link>https://nathancatania.com/posts/upgrade-your-ps4-to-an-ssd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nathancatania.com/posts/upgrade-your-ps4-to-an-ssd/</guid>
      <description>This guide will work for all models of PlayStation 4, however the location of the hard-drive bay is different between models.&#xA;Replacing your Hard Drive will NOT void your warranty and is covered in an official support article.&#xA;Why would you want to do this? A few reasons. Namely:&#xA;You need more space for games. Many PS4s ship with a 500GB HDD which can be filled quickly.&#xA;You want faster load times.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZTP Juniper devices with Sky Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://nathancatania.com/posts/ztp-juniper-devices-with-sky-enterprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nathancatania.com/posts/ztp-juniper-devices-with-sky-enterprise/</guid>
      <description>1.0 - ZTP Overview Arguably, the best feature of Sky Enterprise is its ability to make Zero Touch Provisioning (ZTP) of Juniper devices a breeze. You no longer need to mess around with DHCP options, nor do you need to ensure your config files are accessible via FTP.&#xA;Sky Enterprise allows you to ZTP your devices through the concept of &amp;ldquo;ZTP Templates&amp;rdquo;. A ZTP template is the Junos configuration you wish to apply to a device, exported in XML format (instead of the normal C-like syntax of Junos), with some variables added in - allowing you to re-use the same template across multiple devices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connect Juniper Sky Enterprise to Aerohive HiveManager</title>
      <link>https://nathancatania.com/posts/connecting-skyenterprise-to-aerohive-hivemanager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nathancatania.com/posts/connecting-skyenterprise-to-aerohive-hivemanager/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Juniper Sky Enterprise is a neat little application that can manage and provision SRX, EX, and NFX series products from Juniper Networks. Sky Enterprise also allows you to monitor (but not configure) any Aerohive APs that you have deployed, however the documentation on how to do so is hidden away on the OneConfig website.&#xA;This post will walk through the process of adding your Aerohive APs to your Sky Enterprise inventory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlock or change the super password for Junos Space 17.2, 18.X</title>
      <link>https://nathancatania.com/posts/unlocking-or-changing-the-super-password-for-junos-space-172r1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nathancatania.com/posts/unlocking-or-changing-the-super-password-for-junos-space-172r1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For Junos Space and its associated applications, if you have forgotten the password to the super account (or have locked yourself out of the account), you can reset the password and/or unlock the account by modifying the super user&amp;rsquo;s entry in the build_db DB of MySQL; via the Unix CLI in Space&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;debug&amp;rdquo; mode.&#xA;However in release 17.2R1, the default password of the jboss user (which is required in order to access the MySQL CLI in the first place) has changed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploy a multi-node, multi-server Kafka Cluster with Docker</title>
      <link>https://nathancatania.com/posts/deploying-a-multi-node-kafka-cluster-with-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nathancatania.com/posts/deploying-a-multi-node-kafka-cluster-with-docker/</guid>
      <description>What is Kafka? Essentially:&#xA;Kafka is an open-source, very scalable, distributed messaging platform by Apache. It is designed to handle large volumes of data in real-time efficiently.&#xA;Kafka works on the concept of a &amp;ldquo;publish-subscribe&amp;rdquo; methodology:&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Producers&amp;rdquo; will push content to the Kafka cluster, to a destination &amp;ldquo;topic&amp;rdquo;. A Kafka cluster is managed by Zookeeper, and can contain one or more &amp;ldquo;Brokers&amp;rdquo;. Brokers manage topics and the associated ingress and egress messages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Docker CE on an Air Gapped RHEL system</title>
      <link>https://nathancatania.com/posts/installing-docker-on-red-hat-with-no-internet-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nathancatania.com/posts/installing-docker-on-red-hat-with-no-internet-access/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I recently completed a deployment inside a customer&amp;rsquo;s lab involving several containerized services, in which the server instances provided were not permitted to have direct access to the internet. To add to the issue, the instances themselves were running RHEL 7.3 with no active subscription.&#xA;There were several problems in play here:&#xA;Docker only make their Enterprise Edition (EE) compatible with RHEL. The usual free Community Edition (CE) is not officially supported.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
