<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>netskope on Nathan Catania</title>
    <link>https://nathancatania.com/tags/netskope/</link>
    <description>Recent content in netskope on Nathan Catania</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nathancatania.com/tags/netskope/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Netskope Cloud Exchange</title>
      <link>https://nathancatania.com/posts/deploy-netskope-cloud-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nathancatania.com/posts/deploy-netskope-cloud-exchange/</guid>
      <description>The thoughts, and opinions in this post are my own and do not reflect those of Netskope. All content in this post is my own and is not endorsed by Netskope. Please follow this guide at your own risk.&#xA;Changelog:&#xA;1st Mar, 2022: Initial post 7th Dec, 2022: Updated guide for Cloud Exchange 4.0. What is Cloud Exchange? Cloud Exchange (CE) is a platform (free for all Netskope customers) that facilitates the exchange of information between your various security and operations platforms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netskope Quick Start Guide</title>
      <link>https://nathancatania.com/posts/netskope-quick-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nathancatania.com/posts/netskope-quick-start/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: Any thoughts or opinions in this article are my own and do not reflect those of Netskope. I am a Netskope SE who worte this guide in his own time to assist Netskope customers. Please lodge a PR on GitHub to correct any mistakes or inaccuracies.&#xA;The Quick Quick Start There are 2 fundamental steps required to deploy Netskope in your environment:&#xA;1. Add users to the platform. This is typically done by integrating with your Identity Service (ie: Azure AD, Okta) using SCIM (API), or synchronizing your on-premise Active Directory using the Directory Importer Tool.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How-to Configure SSO for Netskope Cloud Exchange</title>
      <link>https://nathancatania.com/posts/sso-cloud-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nathancatania.com/posts/sso-cloud-exchange/</guid>
      <description>The thoughts and opinions in this post are my own and do not reflect those of Netskope. Please follow this guide at your own risk.&#xA;This post will cover how to configure Single-Sign-On (SSO) for the Netskope Cloud Exchange (CE) platform; specifically for Azure AD and Okta. This will allow you to manage administrator access to CE from within your existing Identity Provider (IdP), rather than configuring administrators within the platform manually.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
